rapidapi.com 2017-05-13

# RapidAPI

This is the privacy policy (“Privacy Policy”) that governs how we, Rapid Software Solutions Ltd. (“Rapid”, “we”, “our” or “us”), use Personal Information (defined below) that we collect, receive and store about individuals in connection with the use of: (i) the websites imrapid.co, rapidapi.com, and any other website that we operate (each, together with its sub-domains, content and services, a “Site”); and (ii) the Rapid software as a service application and any other software application that we license (each individually, and collectively, the “Application”). The Site, the Application, and any other products and services we make available, are individually and collectively referred to herein as the “Services”. This Privacy Policy does not govern the Customer Content stored on the website rapidapi.io, nor any websites or web services that our users operate using the Services. 

1\. Introduction. We have implemented this Privacy Policy because your privacy, and the privacy of other users, is important to us. This Privacy Policy explains our online information practices and the choices you can make about the way your Personal Information is collected and used in connection with the Services. “Personal Information” means any information that may be used, either alone or in combination with other information, to personally identify an individual, including, but not limited to, a first and last name, a personal profile, an email address, a home or other physical address, or other contact information. 

2\. Website and Application Terms of Use. This Privacy Policy forms part of our Website Terms of Use which is available at [<https://rapidapi.com/legal/websiteTerms.html>] (“Website Terms”) and the Application’s Terms of Use which can be viewed from within your account on the Application and which you accepted prior to using the Application for the first time (“Application Terms”). Any capitalized but undefined term in this Privacy Policy shall have the meaning given to it in the Website Terms, or the Application Terms (collectively, the “Terms”), as applicable. 

3\. Consent and Modification. You are not legally obligated to provide us Personal Information, and you hereby confirm that providing us Personal Information is at your own free will. By using the Services, you consent to the terms of this Privacy Policy and to our collection, processing and sharing of Personal Information for the purposes set forth herein. If you do not agree to this Privacy Policy, please do not access or otherwise use the Services. We reserve the right, at our discretion, to change this Privacy Policy at any time. Such change will be effective ten (10) days following posting of the revised Privacy Policy on the Site, and your continued use of the Services thereafter means that you accept those changes. 

4\. What Personal Information We Collect and How We Collect It. We do not currently require you to provide Personal Information in order to have access to general information available on the Site. But, we do receive and/or collect Personal Information from you in the following ways: 

4.1. Account. In order to use certain services that we offer via the Site and/or Application, you may be required to create an account (“Account”). We may offer different options to create an Account, including: 

(a) Online Registration Form: You may choose to complete and submit an online registration form. You will be asked to provide us with certain mandatory information such as your name, email address, and also a password that you will use for your Account. You may also optionally provide a mobile number for 2-step verification. 

(b) Third Party Accounts: You may choose to create an Account by clicking on a ‘connect’ or ‘sign-in’ button that we may display on the Site or Application for a designated third party website or service (each a “Third Party Account”) such as Facebook. Doing so will enable you to link your Service Account and your Third Party Account. If you choose this option, then you will be required to approve the connection as well as the types of information (which may include Personal Information such as, at minimum, your email, full name, and Facebook ID) that we will obtain from your Third Party Account and the types of activities that we may perform in connection with your Third Party Account. Please note that in order to use this option, you will need to have, and may need to be signed-in to, an existing Third Party Account. 

Regardless of which method you choose to register your Account, we may send an email to your nominated email address to instruct you how to confirm your registration. 

4.3. Share with Friends Service. The Site and/or Application may enable you to invite your friends to use our Services by sending them an invitation email or message. You may do so by: (i) using the Site and/or Application to send or post an invitation message via your Third Party Account; and/or (ii) using the Site and/or Application to send an invitation email to your friend’s external email address (for example, a gmail address). If you send or post an invitation message, we may collect Personal Information about the recipient such as their email address. 

4.4. Profile. Some parts of the Site and/or Application may enable you to build a public profile in connection with your Account (“Public Profile”). Your Public Profile will include your name and other information that you manually choose to include in your Public Profile. If you publish your contact information as part of your Public Profile, you may receive unsolicited messages from other users of the Services or the public. 

4.5. Purchases. The Site and/or Application may include the option to purchase certain products or services from us. If you choose to make a purchase we will direct you to tools, software or services of third-party service providers to process transactions on our behalf, in which case you acknowledge that we do not control the privacy practices of such service providers and you agree to review and be bound by the terms of use and privacy policy of any such third-party service providers. 

4.6. Log Files. We may make use of log files. The information inside the log files includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, type of browser, Internet Service Provider (ISP), date/time stamp, referring/exit pages, clicked pages and any other information your browser may send to us. We may use such information to analyze trends, administer the Services, track user’s movement around the Services, and gather demographic information. 

4.7. Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies. Our Services may utilize “cookies”, anonymous identifiers and other tracking technologies in order to for us to provide our Services and present you with information that is customized for you. A “cookie” is a small text file that may be used, for example, to collect information about activity on the Services. Certain cookies and other technologies may serve to recall Personal Information, such as an IP address, previously indicated by a user. Most browsers allow you to control cookies, including whether or not to accept them and how to remove them. You may set most browsers to notify you if you receive a cookie, or you may choose to block cookies with your browser. For more information about the way cookies are used by us, and your options for controlling their use, please read our Cookie Policy, available at [https://www.rapidapi.com/legal/cookiePolicy.html]. 

4.8. Mobile Device Data. We may collect limited information from your mobile device in order to provide the Services. Such information may include your mobile device type, mobile device id, and date and time stamps of Services use. In addition, we may deploy tracking technologies within the Services to help us gather aggregate statistics, but we will not use Personal Information for such purposes. 

4.9. Google Analytics. The Site may use a tool called “Google Analytics” to collect information about use of the Service. Google Analytics collects information such as how often users visit the Service, what pages they visit when they do so, and what other sites they used prior to coming to the Service. We use the information we get from Google Analytics to maintain and improve the Service and our products. We do not combine the information collected through the use of Google Analytics with personally identifiable information. Google’s ability to use and share information collected by Google Analytics about your visits to and use of the Service is restricted by the Google Analytics Terms of Service, available at http://www.google.com/analytics/terms/us.html, and the Google Privacy Policy, available at http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/. You may learn more about how Google collects and processes data specifically in connection with Google Analytics at http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/. You may prevent your data from being used by Google Analytics by downloading and installing the Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on, available at https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/. 

5\. Publicly Available Information. In order to provide the Services to you, your Public Profile and any content that you post on or via the Services, such as the Customer Content and User Submissions, will be collected and used by us or by other third-party service-providers in accordance with the Terms. By uploading your Customer Content and User Submissions, you confirm that your Customer Content and User Submissions may be publicly available to other users of the Services, and may also be accessed and used by people off the Services, such as the users of any site or app you create using the Services. You control, and are solely responsible for, the extent of public access to your Customer Content through the design of any software that you create using the Services. We, therefore, strongly encourage you to adopt your own privacy policy with your own users and to only post information in your Customer Content in accordance with that privacy policy. 

6\. The Way We Use Personal Information. If you submit or we collect Personal Information through the Services, then we may use such Personal Information in the following ways, via any applicable communication channel, including e-mail, SMS, etc.: 

6.1. We will use your Personal Information to provide and improve our Services, to send you marketing/advertisement communications that we believe may be of interest to you, to contact you in connection with the Services and certain programs or offerings that you may have registered for, and to identify and authenticate your access to the parts of the Services that you are authorized to access. 

6.2. We may use your designated email address to: (i) send you updates or news regarding the Services and our products; (ii) send you emails for help or assistance in using the Services; and/or (iii) respond to a “Contact Us” or administrative request (for example, to change your password). 

6.3. If you choose to send your friend an invitation email or message we will use the contact information that you provide, or make available, to automatically send your friend an invitation email or message. Your name and email address may be included in the invitation email or message. 

6.4. We may transfer your Personal Information to our local or foreign subsidiaries or affiliated companies for the purpose of storing or processing such information on our behalf. Such information may be transferred to other countries. We require that these parties agree to process such information in compliance with our Privacy Policy. 

6.5. We may share your Personal Information with our third party service providers and partners, but only to assist us with our business operations and to provide our Services to you and other users. Such information may be transferred to other countries. We use commercially reasonable efforts to only engage or interact with third party service providers and partners that post a privacy policy governing their processing of Personal Information. 

6.6. We may disclose your Personal Information or any information you submitted via the Services if we have a good faith belief that disclosure of such information is helpful or reasonably necessary to: (i) comply with any applicable law, regulation, legal process or governmental request; (ii) enforce our Terms, including investigations of potential violations thereof; (iii) detect, prevent, or otherwise address fraud or security issues; or (iv) protect against harm to the rights, property or safety of Rapid, our users, yourself or the public. 

7\. Use of Anonymous Information. We may use Anonymous Information (as defined below) or disclose it to third party service providers in order to improve our Services and enhance your experience with the Services. We may also disclose Anonymous Information (with or without compensation) to third parties, including advertisers and partners. “Anonymous Information” means information which does not enable identification of an individual user, such as aggregated information about you or your users’ use of our Services. You agree to inform your users of this data collection practice in your own privacy policy. 

8\. Opting In/Out. You may choose to receive future promotional, advertising, or other Services-related emails from us at the time you create your account. If you wish to opt-out of such emails in the future, you may do so at any time by selecting an unsubscribe link at the bottom of each email that we send. Please note that even if you opt out of receiving the foregoing emails, we may still send you a response to any “Contact Us” request as well as administrative emails (for example, in connection with a password reset request) that are necessary to facilitate your use of the Services. 

9\. Choice. At all times, you may choose whether or not to provide or disclose Personal Information. If you choose not to provide mandatory Personal Information, you may still visit parts of the Services but you may be unable to access certain options, programs, offers, and services that involve our interaction with you. 

10\. Access/Accuracy. To the extent that you do provide us with Personal Information, we wish to maintain accurate Personal Information. If you would like to delete or correct any of your other Personal Information that we may be storing, you may submit an access request by sending an email to [privacy@rapidapi.com](mailto:privacy@rapidapi.com). Your email should include adequate details of your request. 

11\. Links to and Interaction with Third Party Products. The Services may enable you to interact with or contain links to your Third Party Account and other third party websites, mobile software applications and services that are not owned or controlled by us (each a “Third Party Service”). We are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such Third Party Services. Please be aware that the Third Party Services may collect Personal Information from you. Accordingly, we encourage you to read the terms and conditions and privacy policy of each Third Party Service that you choose to use or interact with. 

12\. Children’s Privacy. The Services are not structured to attract children under the age of 13 years. Accordingly, we do not intend to collect Personal Information from anyone we know to be under 13 years. If we learn that we have collected Personal Information from a child under 13 years, we will delete that information as quickly as possible. If you believe that we might have any such information, please contact us at privacy@rapidapi.com. 

14\. Merger, Sale or Bankruptcy. In the event that we are acquired by or merged with a third party entity, or in the event of bankruptcy or a comparable event, we reserve the right to transfer or assign Personal Information in connection with the foregoing events. 

15\. California Privacy Rights. California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits our customers who are California residents to request certain information regarding our disclosure of Personal Information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please send an email to [privacy@rapidapi.com](mailto:privacy@rapidapi.com). Please note that we are only required to respond to one request per customer each year. 

16\. Our California Do Not Track Notice. 

We do not currently respond or take any action with respect to web browser “do not track” signals or other mechanisms that provide consumers the ability to exercise choice regarding the collection of personally identifiable information about an individual consumer’s online activities over time and across third-party web sites or online services. We may allow third parties, such as companies that provide us with analytics tools, to collect personally identifiable information about an individual consumer’s online activities over time and across different web sites when a consumer uses the Services. 

17\. Deletion of Content from California Residents. If you are a California resident under the age of 18 and a registered user, California Business and Professions Code Section 22581 permits you to remove content or Personal Information you have publicly posted. If you wish to remove such content or Personal Information and you specify which content or Personal Information you wish to be removed, we will do so in accordance with applicable law. Please be aware that after removal you will not be able to restore removed content. In addition, such removal does not ensure complete or comprehensive removal of the content or Personal Information you have posted and that there may be circumstances in which the law does not require us to enable removal of content. 

18\. Commitment. We are committed to protecting your privacy. Protecting your privacy online is an evolving area, and we are constantly evolving our Service to meet these demands. If you have any comments or questions regarding our Privacy Policy, or your Personal Information that we may be storing and using, please contact us at [privacy@rapidapi.com](mailto:privacy@rapidapi.com). 

**Last updated: August 20, 2015**
